Artem Pakhomov

Lead PHP Developer from Ukraine

Phone: +380 (50) 027-93-00 Email: setnemo@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/setnemo

LinkedIn: Artem Pakhomov



I have been working in the web industry for the past eight years. I'm writing a code according to SOLID, KISS, YAGNI, DRY. I'm publishing all my pet projects on Github as I adore open source. I'm a back-end developer, and I fancy creating telegram bots. During the russian invasion of Ukraine, I started to be a volunteer. From 01/2023 - I was COO of "Let's See The Victory." Charity Foundation works on a project with neuroprosthesis for blind people. This CV was created on PHP with GitHub Actions, as I can't live without automation.

Technologies

PHP: OOP, SOLID, REST, TDD, PHPDoc, PSR, MVC, Composer, Laravel

DB and Brokers: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ

Tests: PHPUnit, Codeception

Git: understand rebase, reflog, squash, cherry-pick, soft/hard reset, etc

Unix: used ArchLinux, Debian, Mint, Ubuntu, macOS, vim, grep, sed, awk, ssh, etc

Containers: docker, k8s

Dev environment: nginx/docker, Postman, PHPStorm, xDebug, Makefile

Experience

Senior PHP Developer at NDA (~300 mln users) Remote, Ukraine - 04/2022 - Present

- Anti-Fraud department tasks
- With my team, I created a system of automatic selection of the optimal task, which is ideal for execution at a specific moment for a specific co-worker. For the calculation, we used more than 5 levers converted into percentiles to obtain the sum of importance for each type of task. The employee had to choose one of 24 types of tasks, and this system allowed to choose the most optimal type of task, taking into account such options as how long the employee has been doing the same, how long this task has been waiting for completion, what is the average performance of the employee for this type of tasks, etc.
- Other project details are prohibited by non-disclosure agreement

Lead PHP Developer at Blockster Kyiv, Ukraine - 04/2021 - 03/2022 ~1 year

- I implemented and realized with my team the way which provided migration from old legacy code (white label) to the modern application (Laravel)
- Under my leadership, my team teaches to work with TDD technics. My team implemented a
 metrics system (raw data to Postgres, aggregated to Prometheus) and an experiment (for A/B
 testing on the back-end) system, providing more understanding of our product user
 experience. These two projects were the first projects in the company with over 80 percent
 test coverage.
- I mentored the back-end developers team (~5 back-ends) and helped other teams with processes, cross-team developing, and sharing knowledge.
- My vision provided changes for processes: move gitlab issues to Jira (create automation), create workflows for all colleagues(design/development/qa), taught colleagues to use it.
- Also, I created some automation for many things, which made it more transparent and proper decomposition/developing/testing/duty flow.

PHP Developer at airSlate Inc Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 04/2021 ~2 years

- I wrote code with tests and documentation, made code review. I deployed on dev/rc for testing, deployed releases on production
- I configured alert rules and checking the cause of alerts, working with metrics

Experience

PHP Developer at Wallet Factory Kyiv, Ukraine - 01/2019 - 05/2019 ~6 months

- Back-end development for a Fin-tech mobile application.
- PHP 7+, OpenSSL, payments API integrations
- API integrations for sales/discounting etc

PHP Developer at MakeTop Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2015 - 12/2018 ~3,5 years

- · I wrote implementation for search engine optimization
- I was working with popular CMS and self-hosted websites.

Education

Software Architect UNIT Factory, Kyiv - 09/2017 - 11/2018

I was one of 5 students with the best marks in UNIT Factory (course 2017), I completed the 3-year program (Ecole 42, France) in 1 year. UNIT Factory StudHub. Volunteering in Exam. Event organization. Meet-up organization.

Languages

English - Professional proficiency, (fluent intermediate)

Ukrainian - Native

Volunteer experience

SuperGrandchildren at Happy Lunch

CO "Lifelover" happyold.com.ua

Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 03/2020

Helped to feed poor elderly people

Military/Medical Volonteer at russian invasion of Ukraine 2014-2023

Lviv, Ukraine - 03/2022 - 01/2023

Raised donates more than \$270,000 for Kevlar helmets, a night vision scope, tactical goggles and other equipment, medical support for a combat engineers battery of the Ukrainian Armed Forces from Donetska region

Co-owner Charitable organization «Charity Foundation «LET'S SEE THE VICTORY», Kyiv - 01/2023 - Present.

The mission of our non-profit is to help people who have lost their sight regain sight, especially those who have lost sight due to the war. Because eye transplantation is not possible, people who have lost their sight and wish to regain vision are not most doctors' first priority. The founders of this non-profit comprise of people who already know about this type of suffering, and want to change this. Vladyslav Yeschenko lost his eyes in the war, and Artem Pakhomov was looking for technologies that exist for lost eyesight, or are currently being researched abroad. Our research has found a procedure that can make a blind person partially sighted, but it is still being tested. The fund plans to cooperate with researchers of this technology or otherwise create conditions so that Ukrainians who have lost their sight have access to this technology. Adapting this technology is now the number one mission of the non-profit, and our foundation is in talks with researchers to expand its potential.